# Des Gouttes & Associés



## Robert Fiechter

**Partner** Attorney at Law, LL.M. Deputy Judge at the Geneva Court of Justice; Deputy Secretary of the Supervisory Board CDB

#### Languages

English, (Swiss-)German, French

#### **Contact Details**

T + 41 22 704 30 50 robert.fiechter@desgouttes.ch

# **Expertise**

## Fraud, Financial Crime and Asset Recovery

Robert Fiechter advises banks, trading companies, and financial institutions on asset protection and asset recovery in connection with complex international fraud cases. He is a Founding Member of the International Fraud Group (www.internationalfraudgroup.com), a group of specialized fraud lawyers active across more than 20 financial centers and offshore jurisdictions around the world, focused on securing injunctions, asset recovery and trust busting remedies.

## **Banking and Finance**

As deputy secretary of the Supervisory Board CDB (Swiss Bank Codes of Conduct), Robert Fiechter has extensive experience in banking regulatory issues, international administrative and criminal legal assistance. Robert Fiechter regularly handles procedures involving international administrative assistance concerning requests emanating from the SEC and the French COB as well as from the US Department of Justice and other foreign criminal prosecution authorities.

#### **Private Clients**

Robert Fiechter advises high networth individuals and families on asset protection and conveyance of estates. He also acts as executor in domestic and international successions.

## Education

1980

1980	University of New Orleans, Tulane Law School, LL.M.
1978	Admission to the Geneva Bar
1976-1978	University of Geneva, Licence en droit

## Professional Experience

1982	Joined Des	s Gouttes &	Associés	
1980-1981	•	Assistant, aw School, (	University Geneva	of

## Other Activities

2008	Deputy Secretary of the Supervisory Board CDB (Agreement on the Swiss Banks' Codes of Conduct regarding the exercise of due diligence), Berne
2007	Deputy Judge at the Court of Justice (Appellate Court), Geneva
2007-2011	President of the Arbitral Tribunal SRO Post
1996-2006	Deputy Judge at the Tribunal of First Instance of Geneva

# **Memberships**

Geneva Bar Association (OdA), Swiss Bar Association (SAV), Swiss-American Chamber of Commerce, International Fraud Group